《綠箭俠》前情回顧
Previously, on "Arrow"...
今晚我們齊心協力
Tonight we rise up as one
奪回這座城市
and take back this city.
斯萊德還有二十個跟他一樣的人
Slade's got 20 guys just like him,
我們沒辦法阻止他
and we have no way to stop him.
米拉庫魯  我們要用它製造解藥
Mirakuru. We're going to use it to make a cure.
斯萊德承諾讓我當市長
Slade promised me city hall,
他兌現了這個承諾
and he delivered.
我知道他也向你作出過承諾
I understand he made you a promise, too.
這件事結束之前  還有一個人必須得死
There is still one person who has to die.
他們人太多了  我們打不過
There's so many of them! We can't fight!
不需要
We're not going to.
勞蕾爾
Laurel.
Laurel?
勞蕾爾
Laurel!
你殺了我
You killed me...
我來還你一個人情
let me return the favor.
你殺不了我
You can't kill me.
你並非不可戰勝
You're not invincible.
差不多了
Close enough.
勞蕾爾
Laurel!
奧利弗
Oliver!
你還好嗎
Are you OK?
隧道塌了
The tunnel collapsed.
我被困住了
I'm trapped.
我只是
I just...
越來越
It's getting really...
難以呼吸了
hard to breathe!
你會沒事的
You are going to be OK.
把你能看見的東西都告訴我
I need you to tell me everything that you see.
石頭  水  還有
Rocks, and water, and--
還有你的弓
and your bow.
看到我的箭袋了嗎
You see my quiver?!
等等  是的  我拿到了
Wait! Yeah, yes, I have it! I have it.
裡面還有多少支箭
How many arrows are in it?
有好幾支
There's a bunch of them.
裡面應該有一支箭是金屬箭頭
There should be one with a metallic head
比其它箭頭都大
that's bigger than the rest of them.
看到了嗎
Do you see it?
這個有什麼用
Why do I need this?
因為這個是爆破箭頭
Because it's an explosive arrow.
你得用它
And you're going to fire it.
你能幫我省點時間和精力嗎
Do you want to save me some time and energy?
告訴我費利西蒂•斯莫克在哪裡
Then tell me where I can find Felicity Smoak.
從那時候起  我一直很想朝她那張
I have been aching to put a bullet
自以為是的小臉上開一槍
in her smug little face ever since the day...
我還以為氣囊要彈出來呢
I really thought the airbags were going to go off.
謝謝幫忙
Thanks for the help.
有奧利弗的消息嗎
Any word from Oliver?
狄格
Dig...
你想怎麼做  再撞她一下嗎
What do you think, hit her again?
快開  快開
Go, go, go, go, go, go, go!
武器室
未經允許  禁止入內
出去  出去
Get out! Get out!
市政廳
市長辦公室  星城中心區地檢署
全城的記者都在趕來
Reports are coming in from all over the city.
星城總院正在準備接收傷者
Starling General is preparing for possible casualties.
軍隊已經從港灣大道南部出發了
Power is out south of Harbor Boulevard.
州長  州長
Governor. Governor.
這種時候派出國民警衛隊
Sending in the national guard at this point
只會造成更大的恐慌
will only cause mass hysteria.
請相信我和我的員警
Trust me and my police force.
我們能夠控制局面
We have this situation under control.
-市長先生  -斯賓塞地檢官
- Mr. Mayor. - D.A. Spencer.
發生了什麼事
What is going on?
有一群帶面具的人在城市裡到處破壞
There are men in masks tearing through the city.
是的  我知道  我們正在努力控制局面
Yes, I know. And we're doing everything we can.
星城一片混亂
星城警署的警力已經全部出動
The SCPD have already mobilized.
不  那些員警處理不了這種情況
No, the police force, they're not equipped to handle this.
你不明白
You don't understand.
我從來沒見過這種狀況
I have never seen anything like this before.
這些  戴面具的人
These--the men in masks,
簡直  簡直就不是人類
It--it's like they're not human.
不是人類
Not human?
凱特  你知道你在說什麼嗎
Kate, do you even hear yourself?
聽著  我知道你很害怕
Look, I know you're scared,
但你得冷靜下來
But you need to pull yourself together.
星城需要我們兩個都能冷靜思考
Starling City needs both of us thinking clearly right now.
為什麼你這麼冷靜
How are you so calm?
星城一片混亂
因為我知道我們能夠度過這一關
Because I know we're going to get through this.
當我們挺過來以後
And when we do,
星城會比以往更強大更美好
Starling City will be stronger and better for it.
我能依靠你嗎
Can I count on you?
我需要你和我攜手作戰
I need you with me on this.
很好
Good.
那麼讓我們一起拯救城市
Then let's save the city together.
星城一片混亂
你離爆破點夠遠了嗎
Are you far enough away from the debris to avoid the blast?
我不知道
I don't know!
如果我射不了那麼遠呢
What if I can't shoot that far?
那把弓是復合材質的  勞蕾爾
The bow's a hybrid compound, Laurel.
它完全能夠做到
It's going to do all the work for you.
你需要做的只是
All I need you to do...
瞄準瓦礫的正中間
just aim at the middle of the debris.
深呼吸
Take a deep breath.
重心放在兩腳之間
Center your feet.
左手握住弓
Left hand on the bow.
把箭放到弓弦上
Place the arrow on the drawstring.
我能行  我能行
OK, OK, OK, OK, OK.
好了  現在
All right, I want you to pull back
拉開弓弦
on the drawstring.
左臂伸直
And keep your left arm straight.
行了嗎
OK?
數到三
You count to three
然後放箭的
and then you just let go.
你能做到
You can do this.
1  2
1, 2...
3!
射得漂亮
Nice shot.
狄格爾  能聽見嗎
Diggle, you there?
是的  奧利弗  我們聽到了
Yeah, Oliver, we hear you.
我們要出來了
We're coming up.
莎拉不見了
Sara's gone.
一定是被斯萊德抓走的
Slade must have taken her.
該死[俄語]
Chert.
那是什麼
What's that?
是聲納  我在監視亞馬遜號
It's sonar. I was monitoring the "Amazo".
她在移動
She's moving.
我們還剩一個魚雷  是吧
We have one torpedo left, right?
是的
Da.
你能讓它沿直線射出去嗎
Could you rig it to fire in a straight line?
我在探索我究竟能做多少
I'm discovering capacity to do many things
我從未想過能做的事
I never thought I would do.
我要你盡可能將潛艇靠近貨船
I need you to get the sub close enough to the freighter
這樣我能遊過去
so that I can swim over.
那你需要魚雷做什麼
Well, then, what do you need torpedo for?
如果一個小時內我和莎拉還沒回來
If Sara and I aren't back in an hour...
你就要擊沉亞馬遜號
you're going to sink the "Amazo".
不許動
Freeze!
你是誰
Who are you?
我是她爸爸
I'm her father.
綠   箭   俠
第二季 第二十二集
爸爸
Dad!
勞蕾爾  感謝上帝
Laurel, thank God.
你沒事吧
Are you safe?
現在沒事了
I am now.
我現在和綠箭俠在一起
I'm with the Arrow.
那  那就好
Well, that's-- that's good.
聽著  我想他還有事要去處理
Now listen, something tells me he's got work to do.
-我要你避開大路  -好的
- I want you off the streets. - Yeah.
勞蕾爾  一定要保持低調
Laurel, please, keep low,
避人耳目  好嗎
keep out of sight, all right?
爸爸  我知道了  你不必  擔心我
Dad, I know, you don't have to worry...about me.
-你沒事吧  -沒事
- You OK?  - Yeah.
你呢
You?
伊莎貝爾襲擊了狄格
Isabel attacked dig
所以我用麵包車撞了她
so I hit her with the van.
是斯萊德的軍隊
Slade's army.
他至少派出了五十個和他一樣的人
He has at least 50 men out there, all like him.
他們無處不在
They're everywhere.
我們要阻止他們
We need to stop them.
我可能有辦法
We might have a way.
尖端科技研究實驗室打來電話
S.T.A.R. Labs called.
他們有解藥了  傳遞員已經在路上了
They have a cure. There's a courier en route.
到哪了
Where is it?
尖端科技研究實驗室
費利西蒂
來電
喂
Hello?
我是費利西蒂•斯莫克  你在哪裡
Hey, it's Felicity Smoak. Where are you?
我想是在第四大街  我不知道發生了什麼
Fourth street, I think. I don't know what happened.
突然冒出一個戴曲棍球面罩的人
A guy in a hockey mask came out of nowhere
襲擊了我的卡車
and attacked my truck.
-請救救我  -在那裡等著
- Please help me. - Stay where you are.
我想動也動不了
I can't move even if I wanted to.
我覺得我腿斷了
I think my leg's broken.
你該去了
You should go.
勞蕾爾  我不會半途拋下你走的
Laurel, I'm not leaving you out here in the middle of this.
我去警局  是往另一個方向走的
The precinct, it's in the other direction.
我會沒事的
I'll be fine.
勞蕾爾
Laurel,
不行
no.
我現在不需要你
I don't need you right now.
但其他人需要你
Everyone else does.
去吧
So go.
去拯救這個城市
Go save the city.
喂  你還在嗎
Hey! You still there?
是的  我在  我已經標記了你的電話
Yeah, I'm here. I pinged your phone.
我們來了
On our way.
請快點
Please hurry.
找到他
Find him.
在過去五分鐘裡
In the last five minutes,
星城警署收到超過200份
SCPD has had over 200 reports
面具男襲擊城市的報告
of masked men attacking the city.
我應該和勞蕾爾一起去
Should have gone with Laurel
確保她能夠到達警局
and made sure she got to the precinct.
她會和她爸爸在一起的  不會有事的
She'll be with her father, she'll be fine.
奧利弗  她不會有事的
She will, Oliver.
好了
All right.
我們離貨船十米遠
We are 10 meters away from the freighter.
但這還是太瘋狂了[俄語]
But still, this is sumasshedshiy.
太瘋狂了  你都不確定她是否在威爾遜那
Crazy. You cannot even be certain that Wilson has her.
阿納托利  你是個好人
You're a good man, Anatoly.
如果這是永別  那麼請多保重
If this is good-bye, be safe.
我會很快再見到你和莎拉的
I will see you soon. You and Sara.
我說過了
I meant what I said.
如果我們一個小時內沒回來
If we're not back in an hour,
你就擊沉貨船然後自己回家
you sink the freighter and get yourself home.
我覺得我可能更喜歡回巴哈馬
I think maybe I prefer Bahamas.
奧利弗
Oliver.
我不知道我們能否再見
I don't know if we will see each other again.
但你要知道咱倆是永遠的朋友
But know that you have made friend for life.
只要你有什麼需要  無論是什麼
If there is anything you need, it does not matter what...
你盡管開口
you have only to ask.
保重[俄語]  我的朋友
Prochnost, my friend.
包 包重
Proch...prochnost.
保重  保  我還要教你俄語
Prochnost...proch... I also teach you to speak Russian.
聽著  我們要在
Listen up. We're going to establish a perimeter
第五大街和亞當斯街交匯點
with check-points at 5th and Adams,
第二大街和金斯利街交匯點設立檢查站
2nd and Kingsley.
我們得創建一個安全區  聽懂了嗎
We got to create a safe zone, you hear me?
這些人到底是誰
Who the hell are these guys?
這些人是敵人
These guys are the enemy.
他們肆意傷害無辜群眾
They're attacking innocents at random,
到處襲擊  引發混亂
creating mayhem and chaos.
我們要去幹掉他們
We need to put them down.
-副隊  -現在就去
- Lieutenant... - Now!
聽我說  你見過這些人嗎
Listen to me, these guys, have you seen them?
你見過他們嗎  他們是幹不掉的
You seen these guys? They do not go down!
我們得叫來國民警衛隊
We got to call in the National Guard.
那是市長的工作
That's a call for the Mayor.
但是他還沒有這麼做
And he hasn't made that yet.
他不會這麼做的
And he won't.
這次事件是布拉德市長發起的
Mayor Blood let this happen.
-什麼  -相信我
- What? - Trust me.
幕後主使是布拉德
Blood's behind this.
即使我相信你
Look, even if I believe you...
我沒那麼大權力
I don't have that kind of authority.
在緊急情況下  警察局長有這個權力
Well, in an emergency, the chief of police does,
快聯繫他
so get him on the line.
局長死了
Chief's dead.
這樣的話
Well, then...
只有一個人可以幫我們了
there's only one more guy we can call.
但你不會喜歡的
You're not going to like it.
治安維持者
The vigilante.
綠箭俠
The Arrow.
副隊
Lieutenant,
我知道他違反了法律
I know he's breaking the law.
但我們現在面對的局面
But what we're up against,
已經不是違法問題了  這關乎生死存亡
it's not about the law. It's about survival.
現在一群蒙面人肆意踐踏我們的城市
We got masks tearing our city to pieces,
我們需要另一個蒙面人來阻止他們
and we're going to need a mask to stop 'em.
聯繫他吧
Make the call.
那好
Ok, let's do it.
還有件事
One more thing--
對眼下的局面  你比我所有手下瞭解得都多
You know more about what's going on over everyone else I got.
我把決策權交給你  你來指揮這些人
I need you making decisions and leading these men...
警探
Detective.
跟我來  我帶你去安全的地方
Follow me. I can get you to safety.
莎拉
Sara...
我們派駐街頭的記者已經失去聯繫
We lost contact with our reporter on the streets,
市政廳
但已經有數十名目擊者證實這群蒙面人
but we have over two dozen confirmed sightings of masked men
在市內多個地點大肆破壞
attacking numerous municipal locations.
官方要求觀眾朋友盡量待在室內
Officials are asking that you stay indoors...
等等
Wait.
-住手  -別  不要
- Stop! - No, no, no!
夠了
Enough!
計劃不是這樣的
This isn't part of the plan!
塞巴斯蒂安
Sebastian?!
我是星城市長
I am mayor of Starling City,
我命令你立即放開她
and I order you to let her go.
我不聽命於你
I don't take orders from you.
糟了
No...
有西婭的消息嗎  她安全嗎
Any word from Thea? Is she safe?
在星城被襲之前
She decided to leave Starling
她就決定離開這裡了
before the attacks started.
離大橋  還有運送人員不到兩英里了
Just under two miles to the bridge. And the courier.
打給你的
It's for you.
怎麼了  警探
What is it, Detective?
-需要我們做什麼  -我們
- How can we help you? - We?
星城所有員警力量
The Starling City Police Force
將全力協助你應對這場危機
is standing with you on this one.
我需要你們協助遏制這些蒙面人
We need help containing the soldiers.
我們正在想辦法
We're working something
阻止他們  但我們需要更多時間
and it may stop them but we need more time.
交給我們  不管你打算做什麼  祝你好運
We can do that. Whatever you're doing, good luck.
祝我們所有人好運
For all our sakes.
想開上橋去只能走這條路
This is the only street that feeds into the bridge.
全速沖過去
Floor it!
小心
Hold on!
狄格
Dig?
狄格爾
Diggle!
我在這
Yeah, yeah.
她還有呼吸嗎
Is she breathing?
-費利西蒂  -她還有呼吸
- Felicity! - Yeah, yeah.
我們得抓緊離開
Then we have to get out of here.
明白
Yeah, I'm on it.
西婭
Thea!
我不是來傷害你的
I'm not here to hurt you.
我憑什麼相信你
Why should I believe you?
你是個殺人犯
You're a murderer!
是個恐怖分子  還是個瘋子
Terrorist, and psychopath!
我並不指望你能理解我的所作所為
I don't expect you to understand what I've done.
現在不會
Not now.
因為我需要更多時間解釋
Not without more time to explain.
你怎麼可能還活著
How are you even alive?
你來幹什麼
Why are here?
我聽說了你母親的事
I heard what happened to your mother.
我需要來確保你的安全
I needed to make sure you were all right.
我需要見到我的女兒
I needed to see my daughter.
我不是你的女兒
I am not your daughter!
對我你什麼都不是
You're nothing to me!
我完全不需要你
And I want nothing from you.
你聽明白了嗎
Do you understand?
明白  但現在
Yes. But right now,
你需要我的幫助
you need my help.
需要我的保護
My protection.
你完全不知道現在外面有多危險  西婭
You have no idea, Thea, how dangerous it is out there.
城市正在崩潰  讓我帶你去安全的地方吧
The city is falling. At least let me take you to safety.
傳說暴君尼祿
They say Nero sang
對著一片火海的羅馬城高聲歡歌
as he watched Rome burn.
現在我明白他的感受了
Now I understand why.
要是莎朵能親眼看到這一切就好了
If only Shado were here to witness this.
莎朵是誰
Who's Shado?
到底是怎麼回事
What the hell is going on?
你手下有個打了藥的
Once of your juiced-up
神經病殺手殺了我辦公室裡的所有人
jack boots just killed my entire office staff,
還扭斷了地區檢察官的脖子
and snapped the district attorney's neck!
-然後呢  -然後
- And? - And...
我們之前可不是這麼說的
And I never agreed to this!
你本來應該叫你的人收手的
You were supposed to call off your dogs.
那是你的計劃  布拉德先生  不是我的
That was your plan, Mr. Blood, not mine.
我們有協議
We had a deal.
你是擔心我不能履行約定嗎
And do you feel that I've not lived up to my end of it?
外面死傷慘重的
Those are innocent people,
都是無辜的平民
dying out there.
你沒必要連他們也殺
You do not need to kill them.
當然有必要
Yes, I do!
我曾對一個人立下重誓
I made a promise to someone once,
而我言出必踐
and I will uphold it.
所以你籌劃這一切
So this really is all about you
真的只是為了傷害奧利弗•奎恩
just trying to hurt Oliver Queen.
我曾對他發誓
I vowed to him
我會奪走他珍視的一切東西
that I would take away everything
殺死所有他愛的人
and everyone he loves.
而他愛這座城市
And he loves this city.
但這座城市
But this city...
也是我的城市
It's mine, too.
不再是了
Not anymore.
到了明天晚上
As of tomorrow night,
這裡就只剩下碎石  灰燼和死亡
it'll be nothing but rubble, ash, and death.
到時候這裡將變成再好不過的
A land only good for one thing.
墳墓
Graves.
莎拉
Sara...
你去哪裡了
Where have you been?
這不重要
Doesn't matter.
你為什麼回來
Why did you come back?
我不知道
I don't know.
這裡沒有屬於我的東西
There isn't anything here for me.
你的家在這裡
Your family's here.
勞蕾爾  你不瞭解我
You don't know, Laurel, about me.
你不知道我是誰  我變成了什麼樣子
About who I am and who I've become.
我只知道你是個英雄
I know you're a hero.
我不是英雄
I'm not a hero...
勞蕾爾
Laurel.
我根本就不是什麼英雄
I am the furthest thing from it.
我是塔爾•莎菲爾
I am "Ta-er Sah-fer."
這是我的新名字
That was my new name.
因為曾經的那個女人
Because the woman that I was...
曾經的那個女孩
the girl that I was,
已經不見了
was gone.
我不會假裝我和你有過
I'm not going to pretend that I've been through
同樣的經歷
anything that you have.
去年我學到的一件事
One thing that I've learned in the past year
就是我們的經歷
is that these things...
不會擊垮我們
they don't break us.
他們造就了我們
They make us who we are.
而我...已經無可救藥了
And what I am... is irredeemable.
你剛剛說的是什麼
What was that word you said before?
塔爾•莎菲爾
Ta-er Sah-fer.
那是什麼意思
What does that mean?
意思是""金絲雀"."
It means "The Canary."
要是你早就喪失了本性
If you're so far gone
而且無可救藥
and so irredeemable...
你為什麼會有這麼美麗的名字呢
then why would they know you by such a beautiful name?
奧利  奧利
Ollie! Ollie!
奧利  奧利  奧利  謝天謝地
Ollie, Ollie, Ollie! Thank God!
奧利  奧利
Ollie, Ollie...
跟我來
Come with me.
來  跟我來
All right, come with me.
這個潛艇就在貨船旁邊
The sub is right alongside the freighter.
你遊過去就可以了
You just need to swim, OK?
好
OK.
你怎麼還不走
OK, what are you doing?
我還不能走
I can't leave yet.
奧利  走吧
Ollie, come on.
-解藥  -不
- The cure. - No!
我不能把斯萊德留下
I can't--I can't leave Slade behind.
我不能  就這麼丟棄他
I'm not just going to-- I'm not just going to write him off.
是我們給他打的米拉庫魯
We injected him with the Mirakuru.
是我打的  奧利
But it was me-- Ollie.
我為了你放棄了莎朵
I chose you over Shado.
我  我只想回家
I--I just--I just want to go home.
我只想見到我的家人  奧利
I just want to see my family, Ollie.
我不想死
Please, I don't want to die.
走吧  求你了
Come on, please!
我必須這麼做
I need to do this.
我要救回我的朋友
I need to save my friend.
我至少得試一試
I need to at least try.
到潛艇裡去
Get to the sub.
保護自己
Get safe.
沒有你我就不去了
Not without you.
莎拉
Sara...
走吧
Come on.
是爸爸
It's dad.
喂
Hello?
勞蕾爾  你在哪裡
Laurel, baby, where are you?
55街和阿爾弗雷德路口  這有幾個路障
55th and Alfred-- there were a few roadblocks.
你沒事吧
But you're OK?
沒事  莎拉和我在一起
Yeah. Sara's with me.
好  你們兩個都待在原地
Right. Ok. Listen, stay there, both of you.
我馬上過去
I'm on my way.
-我能自己走  -他在哪裡
- I can walk. - Where is he?
手機定位顯示他在500尺半徑以內
The cell phone GPS says he should be within a 500-foot radius.
我打給他
I'll call him.
你在哪裡
Hey, where are you?
我們到了  你在哪  按下喇叭
We're here, where are you? Honk your horn.
好  等下
Cool. Hold on.
等等  我看到你的腳了
Wait! I can see your feet.
你就在我車旁了
You're standing right outside my car.
那不是我們
That's not us.
不
Oh, no!
東西沒了
It's gone.
當前情勢非常緊張
The situation has intensified
當局正在全力控制
as officials struggle to contain
這次前所未見的對我市的攻擊
this historic assault gripping our city.
威爾遜先生  這是你要的東西嗎
Mr. Wilson, is this what you're looking for?
對  就是這個
Yes, it is.
我剛跟星級實驗室的西斯科通過電話
I just got off the phone with Cisco at S.T.A.R. Labs...
他們送過來的是全部的解藥
The cure they sent us was all they had.
而且他們用完了我們給的米拉庫魯
And they used all the Mirakuru that we gave them,
所以他們沒辦法再做了
so they can't make more.
沒有解藥我們就沒法阻止斯萊德的人
We can't stop Slade's men without the cure.
我們會找到其他方法的
We'll find another way.
沒有其他方法
There is no other way!
狄格爾  鑄造廠被占領了
Diggle, the foundry's been compromised
我們得把羅伊救出來
and we need to get Roy out of there.
我現在就去
I'm on it.
我不知道  費利西蒂
I didn't know, Felicity.
五年前  我和現在完全不同
Five years ago, I was a completely different person.
我從來...
And I had...
不知道竟然會...
no idea that something like this was even...
發生這種事  我想像不到
possible. I couldn't have imagined.
你和狄格爾找我回星城的時候
When you and Diggle brought me back to Starling City,
我對我自己發誓  絕對不會
I made a vow to myself that I would never let anything
讓爆炸慘劇之類的事再次發生
like the undertaking happen again.
現在發生的一切都不是你的錯
What's happening now is not your fault.
不  這是我的錯
Yes, it is.
我辜負了這座城市
I have failed this city.
辜負了姚飛
Yao Fei.
莎朵  湯米
Shado. Tommy.
我父親  我母親
My father, my mother.
我只是想緬懷這些人
All that I have ever wanted to do is honor those people.
那你就要繼續戰鬥下去
You honor the dead by fighting.
你的戰鬥還沒有結束
And you are not done fighting!
馬爾科姆•梅林
Malcolm Merlyn,
伯爵  同步信號之王
the Count, the Clock King,
三合會  每一個想要傷害這座城市的人
The Triad--everyone who is trying to hurt this city,
都被你阻止了
you stopped them.
所以你也會阻止斯萊德的
And you will stop Slade.
-我不知道該怎麼做  -我也不知道
- I don't know how. - Neither do I.
但我知道兩件事
But I do know two things.
你不是一個人在戰鬥
You are not alone.
而且我相信你能做到
And I believe in you.
爸爸在哪  他現在應該到了
Where's dad? He should be here by now.
你應該去個更有利的位置
You should get to a better vantage point.
來人啊  救命啊
Somebody help! Please, help!
待在這別動
Stay here.
來人啊  救命啊
Someone help! Please help!
救命啊
Someone help!
救命
Please!
我女兒還在裡面  我救不了她
My daughter is still inside, I couldn't get to her!
別去  太危險了
Don't, it's too dangerous!
-勞蕾爾  -爸爸
- Laurel! - Dad!
你受傷了嗎
Are you hurt?
沒有  我沒事  我還好
No, I'm fine. I'm OK.
警員DC-52呼叫總部  請回覆
Delta Charlie 52 to central, copy!
警員DC-52呼叫總部  請立即回覆
Delta Charlie 52 to central, please copy me, now!
-警員DC-52呼叫總部  -爸爸
- Delta Charlie 52 to central... - Dad.
她沒事
She's fine.
那是誰
Who was that?
她是金絲雀
That's the Canary.
西婭  求你了  跟我走
Thea, please, come with me.
我不想跟你有關係
I don't want anything to do with you.
我根本不想見到你
I don't want to even see you!
躲在我身後
Stay behind me.
你沒有箭了
You're out of arrows.
你身上還有
You're not!
奧利弗
Oliver...
你的電話
this is your phone.
塞巴斯蒂安•布拉德
來電
你想怎麼樣
What do you want?
和你想的一樣  奧利弗
Same thing you do, Oliver.
趁還來得及  拯救這座城市
To save this city before it's too late.
已經來不及了
It's already too late.
斯萊德•威爾遜的事被你說中了
You were right about Slade Wilson.
我之前應該聽你的
I should have listened to you.
但我已經來了  我能幫助你
But I'm here now and I can help you.
我憑什麼相信你
Why should I trust you?
因為  奧利弗
Because, Oliver...
我有米拉庫魯的解藥
I have the Mirakuru cure.
剩下的毒藥能讓他昏迷多長時間
How much venom do we have to keep him under?
大約兩個小時
Two hours, maybe.
走吧
Let's go.
我需要你陪著羅伊
I need you to stay with Roy.
好的
OK.
奧利弗  約翰
Oliver, John...
我多一句嘴
maybe this is obvious,
你們確定這不是圈套嗎
but are we sure this isn't a trap?
不確定
No.
我得說一句  要是你們不能活著回來
I'm just saying, if you guys don't come back alive,
我會非常生氣的
I'm going to be really pissed.
我小時候經常被噩夢困擾
As a young boy, I was plagued by nightmares.
每天晚上我都會驚醒
Every night, I would wake up
渾身冒冷汗  感到害怕和孤獨
in a cold sweat, frightened and alone.
我一直忘不掉我父親那張臉
It was my father's face that haunted me.
這就是他在我眼中的樣子
And this is how I saw him.
簡直就是絕望的化身
The embodiment of desperation and despair.
我做這個面具是為了克服我的恐懼
I made this mask to conquer my fears.
提醒自己為什麼要戰鬥
And remind myself why I fight,
那就是每一天
every day,
都要給這座城市最絕望的人一個機會
to give this city's most desperate a chance.
奧利弗  我只是想幫助別人
All I ever wanted to do was help people, Oliver.
那你就拿出實際行動來
Then help me believe.
解藥在哪裡
Where is the cure?
斯萊德•威爾遜在兌現
Slade Wilson will not rest
他對你的承諾之前  絕不會罷休
until he honors the promise that he made you.
只要我們實力相當  他很難殺死我
I won't be so easy to kill once we level the playing field.
他還不想殺你
He's not interested in killing you.
除非他已經奪走了一切
Not until he's taken away
你所愛的人和物
everything and everyone you love.
他殺死我母親後
After he murdered my mother,
他說還有一個人要死
he said one more person had to die.
肯定是你最愛的人
Whoever you love the most.
我希望你能用這個打敗他
I hope you can beat him with this.
為了我們所有人
For all our sakes.
等這一切都結束了  我向你保證
And when this is over, I promise you...
我會盡我所能  重建星城
I will do everything in my power to rebuild Starling City.
而且我不僅會讓它恢復原貌
And I won't just make it what it was.
還會讓它變得更好
I will make it better.
就像我一直計劃的那樣
Like I always planned.
你真的以為
You really think...
在發生了這一切之後
after everything that's happened,
就憑你的這些所作所為
after what you've done,
人們還會繼續讓你當市長嗎
that they'll still let you be mayor?
為什麼不
Why not?
他們只知道我在盡力挽救這座城市
No one knows that I've done anything except try to save this city.
如果你告訴別人我那面具的事
And if you tell anyone about my mask,
我也會把你的事抖出來
I will tell them about yours.
做好你該做的事  塞巴斯蒂安
Do what you have to, Sebastian.
我得回去了
I got to get back to it.
你們沒事吧
Hey. Are you guys OK?
你有沒有事
Are you OK?
簡直難以置信  一個戴面具的金髮女子
You wouldn't believe it-- a blonde in a mask
抱著個孩子沖出了大火熊熊的建築物
ran out of a burning building with a kid in her arms.
真是太勇敢了  那個女人是個英雄
It was the bravest thing I've ever seen. That woman's a hero.
你給他了對不對
You gave it to him, didn't you?
我覺得有這個必要
I did what I thought was necessary.
不用擔心  我會跟斯萊德說
Don't worry, I'll tell Slade.
他手裡還有解藥嗎
Does he still have the cure?
沒有
No.
斯萊德  你背叛了...
Slade, you betrayed--
永別了  布拉德先生
Good-bye, Mr. Blood.
我愛過這座城市
I loved this city.
為什麼所有秘方都有顏色
Why does every secret formula have to be a color?
歷史悠久的無色都哪裡去了
Whatever happened to good, old-fashioned clear?
如果我們給斯萊德的戰士注射這個...
All right, so if we inject one of Slade's soldiers with this...
根據星級實驗室的研究
According to S.T.A.R. Labs,
這個會抵消米拉庫魯的藥效
it will counteract the effects.
前提是他們的配方正確
Assuming they got the recipe right.
我們得先測試一下
We need to test it.
不行
We can't.
要把羅伊當做實驗小白鼠嗎
Treat Roy like some kind of lab rat?
費利西蒂
Felicity...
要是不起作用呢
What if it doesn't work?
要是把他害死了呢
What if it kills him?
要是他醒來把我們殺了呢
What if he wakes up and kills us?
我們總得想辦法知道
We need to know. One way or the other.
去把另一扇門關上
Go lock the other door.
好
OK.
莎拉  艾沃的保險箱在哪裡
Sara, where does Ivo keep his safe?
在...  他的書邊上
It's, uh, by his books.
奧利弗
Oliver...
你找什麼呢  小子  這個嗎
What are you looking for, kid? This?
蘭斯警探
Detective Lance.
什麼事
Yeah?
發生什麼事了
What's going on?
怎麼了
What is it?
現在直播的是
You're watching live footage
一支護航軍隊
of an army convoy arriving
抵達星城外郊準備恢復城市秩序
on the outskirts of the city to restore order.
裝甲部隊終於來了
Looks like the cavalry's here, finally.
-可能吧  -什麼意思
- Maybe. - What do you mean?
他們正在占領大橋和隧道
Well, they're taking up positions in the bridges and tunnels.
那是進城的唯一方法
Well, those are the only ways into the city.
對  也是出城的唯一方法
Yeah, and the only ways out.
我一個做軍事情報的哥們
A buddy of mine in military intelligence
曾經跟我說軍隊並不總是軍隊
once told me the army isn't always the army.
但顯然是軍方
But it's clearly the military.
看他們的卡車  制服
The trucks, the uniforms.
但是最近的軍事基地在市政局紀念廳
Except the nearest army base is at Monument Point,
離這裡有300英里遠
which is 300 miles from here.
所以他們怎麼會這麼快就到星城了呢
So how could they mobilize to Starling City so fast?
好吧  如果不是軍隊
OK. So if that isn't the army,
那到底是誰
who the hell are they?
對不起
I'm sorry.
我下不了手
I can't.
是蘭斯  警探
It's Lance. Detective.
-他在嗎  -在
- Are you near him? - Yes.
-你那邊有電視嗎  -有
- Are you near a TV? - Yes.
打開
Turn it on.
你怎麼知道我這個號碼的
How did you get this number?
阿曼達  你在幹什麼
Amanda. What are you doing?
我不懂你的意思  奧利弗
I'm not sure what you mean, Oliver.
阿曼達  那支部隊占領了星城的出口...
Amanda, the troops taking up position at the city's exits--
他們不是軍方的人  是超能力聯合調查組
They're not army, they're A.R.G.U.S.
是你的人  所以你告訴我你到底想幹什麼
Those are your men. So you tell me what you're up to.
阿曼達
Amanda!
斯萊德的追隨者明顯
Slade's followers are a clear
是我們目前的威脅  我不能讓他們
and present danger. I cannot allow them
逃出星城  得控制住他們...
to escape the city. They need to be contained...
不惜任何手段
by any means necessary.
你不能這樣做
You can't.
現在正有一架無人機
There's a drone en route
帶著六枚GBU/43-B炸彈過去
carrying six GBU/43-B bombs,
火力足以將星城夷為平地
enough fire power to level the city.
星城裡還有50多萬平民呢
There are over half a million people in this city.
57萬6千人
576,000.
他們都是無辜的
None of whom deserve to die.
但我也得為其他城市的人考慮
But I have to think about the people in every city.
你說過米拉庫魯會讓人變得堅不可摧
You once told me that Mirakuru made a man virtually unstoppable.
要是我不馬上結束這件事
What could happen to this country,
那對我們國家
this world,
還有整個世界會有什麼後果
if I don't end this here and now?
聽我說
Listen to me.
我有解藥
I have the cure.
我可以阻止斯萊德和他的人
I can stop Slade and his men.
萬一失敗了呢  我不能冒這個險  奧利弗
I can't take the chance you'll fail, Oliver.
阿曼達  求你多給我點時間
Amanda, I just need more time.
對不起
I'm sorry.
只能到黎明之前
You have until dawn.
否則星城就會成為一片廢墟
And then Starling City is a crater.
你想開槍的話
If you're going to use that,
記得關掉保險
you'll want to click the safety off.
我會開槍的
I'll shoot you.
我會的
I will!
我可以從你眼中看到
I can see it in your eyes.
我的眼睛
My eyes.
你的眼睛跟我的一樣
They're just like mine.
雙眼中都充滿了痛苦和憤怒
Both of them filled with pain and anger,
因為我們愛的人都被搶走了
because those we loved were ripped from us.
我失去了我的名字  我妻子
I lost my name, my wife...
湯米
Tommy.
閉嘴
Shut up!
你是這個世界上我唯一的親人了
You're all I have left in this world,
你也失去了一切
and you've lost everything, too.
西婭
Thea.
但是你還有父親
But you still have a father.
你還有...
You still have...